Yusuf Seyrek

Senior Software Developer specializing in **Javascript** development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for web, mobile, IoT, and desktop projects. Enthusiast of architecting and developing multi-platform software/applications. Total 13 years of development experience.

Istanbul & Berlin

+90(535) 483-1480

+49 173 418 9299

seyrek91@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/ yusufseyrek/ https://github.com/yusufseyr

ek

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Fullstack Engineer/Architect/Consultant

Sep 2020 - Now

I am helping startups/scaleups/companies to build their software in the most efficient way and providing them consultancy in software architecture

<u>Swarm Markets GmbH</u>, Berlin — Senior Fullstack Engineer/Tech Lead

Jun 2021 - Now

Swarm Markets is the world's first licensed high-liquidity DeFi protocol.

I worked on building new features on the Swarm Markets platform by architecting FE, coming up with the API design, and planning tasks for BE. Also, worked on writing smart contracts, testing and deploying them. I took full ownership of my projects and help the product team clarify applications specs to ensure the quality of UX. In addition, I built DevOps tools to monitor bugs, and code quality to allow developers to work efficiently.

Pixsy Inc., Berlin — Fullstack Engineer Contract

Sep 2020 - Nov 2020

Pixsy is an online platform for creatives and image owners to discover where and how their images are being used online.

I contributed to the new Pixsy's new Match Viewer project by creating the foundation in the front-end. Covered the topics of; legacy code restraining, global state management, route logic handling, data flow, and component tree creation.

<u>Uberall GmbH</u>, Berlin — Senior Frontend Engineer/Tech Lead

Dec 2017 - Aug 2020

Uberall is a SaaS company that provides software solutions that give companies optimal online visibility — so businesses can easily connect with consumers at all the online touchpoints they have with the local outlets of a brand, from finding, persuading, buying and recommending, to returning as a regular customer.

I've started as a Senior Frontend Engineer and then promoted to be Tech Lead within a year. I've focused on tackling business problems and built solid features with the team.

SKILLS

Javascript OOP (12 yrs)

React & React Native (~7 yrs)

Electron (1 yr)

TypeScript (4yrs)

HTML5 (10 yrs)

Android (3 yrs)

iOS (3 yrs)

Node.js (5 yrs)

SQLite (1 yr)

Rest APIs (6 yrs)

Tizen (1 yr)

Design patterns (6 yrs)

IoT (3 yrs)

C# (3 yrs)

Smart Contracts (~1yr)

DApps (~1yr)

Blockchain (~1yr)

Python (~2yrs)

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Trainer at CoderDojo;
CoderDojo is a global
movement of free,
volunteer-led,
community-based
programming clubs for young
people.

<u>Monument Labs Inc</u>, Istanbul — Senior Software Developer

Jun 2016 - Dec 2017

Monument Labs, Inc. designs and develops hardware and related software that helps users to store, organize, and view photos and videos.

After company-funded I've developed a mobile client with React Native. Also worked on communication(REST API) between the Monument device and client applications design.

Lastly, working on multi-platform desktop client's architecture and development phases.

Nomad Commerce, Istanbul — Lead Frontend Developer

May 2014 - Jun 2016

Nomad Commerce develops fintech and banking softwares for banks and end users

My main responsibility as a lead frontend developer was ensuring code quality by doing code reviews, and helping the team on decision making.

Mostly worked on banking back office projects and cross platform mobile application development.

Marmaraweb, Istanbul — *Software Developer (Mobile, Web)*

May 2011 - Apr 2014

Marmaraweb digital agency develops interactive web pages and mobile applications for corporate customers.

I've worked close to customers to understand their needs easily. After that developed and documented their web and mobile projects to the editorial phase of development.

<u>Yenimedya Electronic Publishing</u>, Istanbul — *Intern*

Jun 2009 - Jun 2010

Yenimedya develops various of leader internet publishing projects in Turkey. I've worked on their game publish web projects using ASP.NET with consuming their Web Services.

Training of Coding Club
-Python Basic Programming
for Kids; This project
describes instruction to
develop algorithmic
thinking,make loops,use if &
else statements, functions
,programs which are
calculator, games and code all
of these members in Python
Programming Language by
Bahcesehir College Secondary
Students.

LANGUAGES

English, Turkish

EDUCATION

Nisantasi University, Istanbul

2017 Dropped

Master of Business Administration

Bahcesehir University, Istanbul

2010 - 2015

B.S. in Computer Education and Instructional Technologies.

Profilo Technical High School, Istanbul

2005 - 2010

Studied programming with .NET and basics of C

PROFESSIONAL REFERENCES

Ercan Erciyes, CEO & Co-Founder of Monument Labs, Inc.

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ercanercives/

+1(312) 725-3461

Semih Hazar, CTO & Co-Founder of Monument Labs, Inc.

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shazar/

+1(312) 384-9684

Umut Gökcen Yılmaz, Manager of Nomad Commerce

https://www.linkedin.com/in/umutgokcen/

+90(536) 859-3449